Now we are at Karolinska Hospital's emergency room.
It was just a little tricky way here you can say
We will start by undressing you
so that we can examine you properly
Okay
Here we'll probably take off and see if we don't need to plaster a little
Should we plaster
Yes, probably the whole bone thus
The whole leg
What have you been out for then
I would do a sketch.
Okay,
Yes it was a long way here.
But now it's time to test the food at a Swedish hospital.
Here we have Anette.
She works as a dietician at the hospital
And the menu that she and her colleagues have produced look so luxurious.
It feels like you're at a restaurant.
How can you afford this
After all, it is a very expensive to keep patients in the hospital.
So everything we can do to get patients prescribed is very important.
If you put money on good food like that
I thought you should come with us into the kitchen and cook some jaw
You really checked out that I'm ready.
I don't feel ready
I think you feel a bit half -back if I am to be honest, but we are driving
Why did we do this
It feels unnecessarily complicated.
I could only go without plaster
Now you have been up in the ward and you were a little hungry
I got a little craving for this lasagna.
I could almost imagine it
I looked like such a guy
You feel a little cat Gustav
After all, there are several liters of bechamel you have there.
You knew it was bechamel, that's impressive
Do you think so
Then we start with a little bechamel in the bottom
So that not everything should get stuck
Then we go with Bolognese
Now we will have some cheese on this then it will be in the oven.
Buh
Aah
It feels more like you're at a restaurant while sitting
And check the menu.
Fun that you say it because that's a bit of the idea.
For many, it is the highlight of the day just because you have happened to something.
There is probably nothing that allows one to eat good food here as well
Then we try to do as we want it ourselves.
Yes, now we have finished all layers
And now pushed into the oven.
Buh
I love the reaction which is a “uh” back
And there the lasagna is ready
No
No there it is inside
When the food is done, it is packed into boxes and cooled down.
When an order comes in, then the food is sent off to the correct department
And there it comes with a robot.
A robot.
Oh now comes
Hop
Is called it
Then we put the food in here
And now drive this to your department
Now it is gassing it here
You are allowed to tread on a little
Takes that elevator up to your department.
What a good
Right
Now it's just that you should go up and receive it and eat.
Thanks for the help
Thank you
Has it gone well.
It has gone well.
Swedish healthcare is wonderful
And what should you do when you are done
with this treatment completely
I'll be happy pensioner.
Sounds nice.
Yes, you become like that you
Take advantage of life more in some way when you have received such a diagnosis
It may be a cliche
But the moment that is most important, as long as one has the ability
Four
A clear four.
I fully agree with you
The hospital gets a four.
Then it was just saying hello to Rolf
Before I finally got to take off the plaster I carried all day
Do you want to bring the home as a souvenir.
The good indeed
Okay, the first rating of the competition is awarded, but we have more challengers.
Soon the elderly and the prison will show what they are going for
But first of all school food.
But we take it from the beginning.
We'll take it over
And now we stand here with Jelica
You are a chef at SVERERS School
Yes, hello and welcome to the Sverker School's
Dining room and kitchen
Thanks
I am responsible chef
My home is here at Sverker School's kitchen
Would you say it is good food at Sverkerskolan
I think the food is excellent
Can I only get a minute.
Yep, it is going well
Today
We visit various institutions that have always been there.
Healthcare, school, elderly care.
I would like to take the opportunity to pay tribute to another
Swedish institution
Oboyen
As this section is in paid
in cooperation with.
Do you hear the sound, the sound of the spoon that mixes an oboy
The sounding after sports training, ringing scents.
The sounding after school trips
The sound that continues today.
That said, a Swedish institution.
And one thing you can forget is how much you can do with oboy
Everyone has it in their pantry
Here, for example, we have some really crispy
Popcorn cookies that take less than a quarter to throw together.
Or as my friend Max taught me when we were little milk, cornflakes and oboy on top.
Or an ordinary oboy.
When winter wines the coldest, there is always oboy there
And it stands for security, joy and adventure.
But basically it is simply a glass of chocolate milk that is
Do you have soup too
And so we have freshly baked bread here too.
You are so incredibly ambitious.
Still, think what an important difference you make for society with your job.
Thank you
Now I get embarrassed
Do you become embarrassed
Why do you get embarrassed
You serve food for hundreds of children every day
It's not just me, it's all my friends.
But can you feel this in here.
Yes I can
That you make a difference
Lena you hold
Teams its, team their won
Lena, you take on this loss
No, I absolutely don't
Don't be sad Lena.
I offer some coffee.
Who has cooked
It's the chef.
They are very good
Thanks so much thanks!
The coffee tastes good
No
You haven't met her
Wouldn't it be fun if you just went in and thanked her for making such good food.
I think she would be very happy.
I think it is very appreciated that you
as well as prepare food for us and that it likes to put down your own time
To work with this to make food for this school.
Thank you for cooking
The heart does this a little extra
While wanting to just, yeah
So that's why it became
You were kind of happy to say that because you appreciate it so much.
That she, like cooking the food we eat
And in the middle of this fine we leave Uppsala.
It was an honor to meet you
Thanks.
I move on.
Bye.
There will be four out of five in grades to the school as well.
Which thus goes up in split first place with the hospital.
Soon we will see if Sweden's largest prisons serve better food than this.
But first of all, we will test the food in elderly care.
So I went to a dementia residence outside Stockholm
And that's why we stand here at Mälar Backen's care and care accommodation with you Stefan
Thank you good day
I like
F*ck yeah
Oh yeah
So if you just take a fish and give a little like this.
It becomes like a giggle as well.
How many portions of food do you make in a day
About 900 in total
Oh damn
Okay, what happens now
I thought we might do some bran.
Semlor
What did you say
Cool us down a bit
Shall we cool down a bit
Sounds that like a plan
Yes, so we kept going and cool down.
Threw snowballs on passersby, mucked quarrels
with each other, made cool greetings and finally
A farewell.
And so we only have one visit left.
Kumlaanstalten outside Örebro
Where we will meet the officer Sofia.
Then we will go into the real prison.
As a person, you have a very exciting story.
You fled to Sweden from Congo about 30 years ago.
Soon 34
And then you have made a rocket career within the Prison Service
And now head of Sweden's largest institution.
Would not describe my career as a rocket
It must be said like a rocket
But we are here to test food today on a prison.
How good is the food?
Very good.
The punishment itself is that they are with us here and will serve their sentence.
Then we also have to take care of them.
Make sure they do not return to crime.
Thus, to maintain a decent standard of living in here.
Reduce the risk of committing new crimes and they will very safely.
Very safe
Thousand thanks
Then I was led towards the prison itself
through quantities of doors, gates, corridors and locks
Until I ended up in a department that was just renovated this day.
And here is literally there
The prisoners at Sweden's largest security prison live.
Yeah not there because it's a cleaning scrub
Yeah okay but there
And here is like a cell.
it's not fun.
No, it's a boring and tough environment they may be in
There is no dance on roses.
How long would I survive in this environment
I have a quarter of a quarter in me.
It depends on which department you sit on.
I would not sit in this department it feels like
maybe not really but i know where you could sit
We have another department
A small fog
Yes a little so
And what we are in.
It is a special department in a way you can say for it.
Here you cook the food yourself
Do you have a knife and stuff.
It is stuck and is stuck properly
If you are here at the same time and talk to someone, then you stand a bit away.
Now my photographer is lucky that he is on the right side.
Here comes some prisoners, big and strong he was on the left
They are quite bitty some of them here
They will not cure me against it I can say
But most are right okay
They are.
They are fun to have and do with
What is it like to work close to them
In my case, I feel that I meet the person, not the crime.
I have to be able to go in
And meet them as an individual and talk to them to make a difference.
I hope you can do anyway
A small, put a small seed of new thinking or rethink.
Here I do not want to again and encourage you can find these little points where you show
That you can see them as people, as people and then you make a difference.
But thank you very much for the round
Now I'm going to the large kitchen where all the food is made.
Hope it tastes.
Thanks
It is green
It's green now
So now we can go in without any prisoners that we meet
They live here right and left.
Exciting
Strange, why do you have scooters.
Can you get you can get
What funny that you react
No she is my queen
The punishment is already to sit here on Kumla.
The food can still be very good
I think
It would be strange if you chefs strained you to make bad food,
Yes but it feels a little wrong
is there a limit and you feel like this
Oh, now it was too good we are still a prison.
So i salt in a little extra then
Nothing like that or
Yes some
What are you?
You understand what this will have to lead to.
I hope you realize
Ne, not sowing singing
I think I read now that you have to sing
No
It won't happen or
There is not a chance.
And in the midst of this wonderful little moment at the prison yard
So it was time for me to decide a winner
And I can say that it was difficult for all the chefs we have met deserves their own tribute
They don't have any magnificent wages.
Many people hardly think that they exist.
Yet they stand out and day in and fight with small budgets
To in their way illuminate the existence of children, pensioners and sick.
But it is a competition and the one that eventually draws
I let the longest straw be surprised by two friends.
Congratulations
But wait it is me
In the big Sweden
Of all the meals that are cooked and that we have won.
Feels huge.
Like having received a Nobel Prize.
I would like to encourage everyone with this one
The benefit to donate a coin to the Child Cancer Foundation.
And of course we will give our profit to the Child Cancer Foundation.